Mehrdad Qasemkhani

DevOps Engineer

gasemkhani.mehrdad@gmail.com

+989385200818

linkedin.com/in/gasemkhani-mehrdad

https://mehrdad-drpc.github.io/

Summary

Software Engineer with more than 4+ years of experience in DevOps & more than 3+ years of coding. A curious learner & excellent team player, searching for a challenging position as a software engineer. I prefer cloud base technologies & DevOps culture & tools.

Keen to work on a software engineer as a system designer.

Longing for chief technology officer.

Experience



DevOps Engineer

Fanap Infrastructure

May 2021 - Present (2 years 11 months)

- Automation of building Spara PAM module by CI Gitlab & Gitlab-runner.
- Automation of deployment Spara PAM module(CD) by Ansible.
- Migration of CI pipelines from Atlassian-Bamboo to Gitlab-CI.
- PAM Dockerizing.
- Produce and Consumption tons of PAM messages by RabbitMQ.
- Log gathering by Elastic & Kibana.
- Synchronization Postgresql databases by Bucardo in active/active mode.
- Load-Balance HTTP(Layer7) & TCP(Layer4) traffic by HAproxy.
- Infrastructure-as-Code(IaC) full automation by Ansible.
- Running up Prometheus & Grafana for all monitoring product.

DevOps Engineer

Respina Networks & Beyond

Feb 2020 - Apr 2021 (1 year 3 months)

- Working on VoIP & Cloud Telecommunication Technologies.
- Communications Platform as a Service CPaaS.
- Session Initiation Protocol.
- Kamailio SIP-Server using signaling section.
- Running Asterisk & Freeswitch soft-switch.
- Maintenance of Respina SIP-Trunk.
- Maintenance of Respina HostedPBX.
- SIP & HTTP Load Balancing.
- High-Availability over SIP & HTTP protocols via VRRP.
- Dockerizing services using docker-dompose.
- Automation of all building process by Gitlab-CI (CI).
- Automation of all deployment process by Ansible (CD).

Backend Developer

Respina Networks & Beyond

Jun 2019 - Feb 2020 (9 months)

- ARI(Asterisk RESTful Interface) development by Python & Django framework.
- Asterisk Call-App-Manager Development over ARI using pure Python.

Python Developer

Kara Tadbir Hooshmand Kish

Jul 2017 - Jun 2018 (1 year)

- Analyzing, designing & developing RESTful API applications to serve subscribers.
- Python, Flask, Neo4j, PostgreSQL, Kong.
- Developing Unit-test & Integration-test.



C Developer

AVA Communication Industries Co. Sep 2016 - Jan 2017 (5 months)

Education



Shamsipour Technical and Vocational College

Associate's Degree, Copmuter 2009 - 2011

Raja

Bachelor of Science (BS) 2011 - 2013

Licenses & Certifications



Certified Kubernetes Administrator (CKA) - Fanavaran Anisa

ILH259910098099

Skills

#Experience in DevOps Engineer, #knowledge in #ComputerScience, good #ability to find #solution, happy to work with #team. • C (Programming Language) • Kubernetes • Continuous Integration and Continuous Delivery (CI/CD) • Programming • High Availability • OOP • Algorithms • Software Development • Shell Scripting